Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a life system so it might play a character
dies and loses all their hearts if they still have some lives.
We're going to respawn our player character back into our game.
So in order to set that system up, if we open up our player blueprint and we want to create a new variable
for this life's.
Make this bearable type afloat.
And just go compile.
And for now we're going to make it to our player character.
We'll start off the game with three lives.
So here on the lights, I'm going to type in three into free space.
If you just right click a look for add custom event and call this respawn.
Whenever our player character dies, we're going to call this respawn custom event.
And if our player character has more than zero likes, so drag a player in A for greater than zero.
So if our player character has more than zero lives, we're going to respawn our player character.
So drink up and look for Branch.
The first thing we're going to do when we respawn our character is make it so that they can move again.
When our player dies, we disable their input so they can't really do anything if their respawn will
enable their input again.
So our right click for enable input and for the player controller, we can right click and we'll get
player controller.
And connect us here.
The second thing we're going to do is give the player their health back and update their heart.
So when our player character dies, they're going to have no hearts.
So we need to update our heart again to make things cleaner and easier.
When our player character dies, we're just going to remove the heart from the viewport.
So after this jump node drag in our heart reference.
And drink up here and look for removed from Arat.
This will make it so our hard will disappear when our character dies.
If we respawn up our character, we'll add our hard back to the viewport.
But before we do this, we're going to drag in our health.
And to our health to be our mctell because one of our dies, their health will be set to zero.
So we just need to give them the health back.
Then after we do this, we'll create a widget.
This widget will be the player HUD.
And we'll just set this as our new HUD reference.
So I'll drive up here and look for set HUD reference and connect this node here.
And then we will add this to the viewport.
After we do this, we're going to move our player character to a safe, restful location.
So if we just drag up here and look for set actor location.
And we're going to move them to a safe location.
So if we create a new variable and call this checkpoint.
Undesirable type.
Change this to be a vector.
And if we go over to the in play, we're going to make our actors starting location their first checkpoint.
So if I just drag in this checkpoint and look for set checkpoint, and then if I just right click,
we'll get actor location.
As soon as our game starts, we'll set our actors starting location as their first checkpoint.
I can now crack in my checkpoint babble and connect us here.
After we do this, we need to tell the game that the player has lost one of their lives.
So if we drag in the life cerebral and drag up here and look for decrement, bloat and just drag in
our lights and set it.
This will subtract the amount of lives we have by one.
Then if you remember, when our character dies, we kind of call this do once event.
If we respawn off that character, we're going to need to reset this.
So I'm just going to right click and look for add custom event and I'll call this reset player death.
And connect us into here.
Then after we do all of this, I will call the Reset Player Deaths custom event.
So the final thing we need to do is make it so that when our player dies, we cool the respawn custom
event.
If we just compile and save this and then head over to our animation folder, go over to the animation
source and select the death animation.
And go over to frame ten.
At frame ten.
Right click and go add, notify new notify and call this restore.
Then if we close this and go to our characters animation blueprint, go over to the respawn function
and drag in our player reference.
And we want to travel here and hold the respawn event that we've just made.
Finally, if we go over to the new state machine, hook up from dire to idle slash run.
So we're going to make it so that we can transition from our diet to our idle start running animation.
In order to enter this transition.
We're going to make sure our player character has more than zero lives.
So I'll drag in my player character reference, drag up here and look for their lives.
We will check to see that this value is greater than zero.
And so I'm just going to try and we'll make sure that our death animation has finished playing.
So I'm just going to right click and look for time remaining death.
And if we don't prepare for this, then and put the value put 0.01.
So the reason we're putting a 0.01 is because for my death animation and I put the respawn notified
quite late towards the end.
So just to be safe, I've made this value 0.01.
Then if we connect us here, we can go compile, save, and we should be able to test this all out.
So if I can play.
And I jump in from my Scampton and I get damaged four times.
I should die and it should call the return.
So I died.
And then it called the respawn custom event and it moved me to my safe location.